- 哇哈哈哈! - 太棒了!
- Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo! - Yeah! all right!
- 嘿! - 看看我们!
- Hey! - Look at us!
这车坐得真爽, 对吧?
Sweet ride, right?
你一定得问, 为什么彼得·帕克
You must be asking, why is peter parker
自封的科学怪才/超级英雄
Self styled science geek slash superhero
能在黑色加长轿车的后座上欢乐呢?
Hanging in the back of a long, black limo?
好吧, 这不是毕业舞会之夜而我也不是总统
Well, it's not prom night and i'm not the president,
但今晚是为了庆祝...
But tonight is cause for celebration--
今天是成绩公布日, 哈利全部搞定
Today was report card day, and Harry nailed it.
敬你, 皮特, 我们都知道
To you peter, we all know that...
哈利没有你只是个C等学生
Harry would be nothing but a "c" student if not for you.
你确实是我儿子也是我们家的好朋友
You're a good friend to my son and this family.
哦, 这你就错了, 奥斯本先生
Oh, you got it wrong, mr. Osborn.
这些都是哈利自己的功劳, 我只是帮他拿书罢了
Harry did all the work. I just carried his books.
嗯, 就像我说的, 你的确是个好朋友
Hmm, like I said, you're a good friend.
队伍需要你
Team needs you.
现在? 呃! 我正要去
Now? aw! I was about to be treated
享受我这辈子最奢华的饭局
To the most incredible meal of my life.
对, 就现在!
Yes, now!
哈利, 我刚刚想起来, 呃
Harry, I just remembered, ah,
梅婶让我回家办点事儿
Aunt may needs me to do something at home.
什么金鱼突发事件
Some sort of gold fish emergency.
- 我得改天了 - 什么? 我们刚到这儿
- I gotta take a rain check. - what? we just got here.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
你知道我很想看狂暴的诺曼
You know I was looking forward to watching stormin' norman
对着经理咆哮, 但任务说来就来
Holler at the maitre de, but duty calls.
嘿, 这么想吧
Hey, look at it this way,
你终于有机会和你爸单独待一会儿了
You'll finally get some good one-on-one time with your dad.
计划进行中
The plan is in motion.
奥斯集团有紧急情况
Emergency at oscorp.
我得走了, 给自己点些
I need to go. order yourself
符合B-这成绩的东西吧
Something worthy of a b-minus.
我讨厌就这样抛弃哈利
I hate having to ditch Harry like that.
应付这些对朋友不够朋友的事
It's stressful having to juggle
实在压力太大
this friends unfriendly stuff.
但是, 责任越大...
But, with great responsibility comes--
...你的责任也就越大
-- great responsibility.
至少我生活里有一部分还在正常运转
At least one part of my life is running on all cylinders.
我已经完全掌握了整套终极蜘蛛侠的东西
I'm figuring out this whole ultimate spider-man thing.
你终于来了, 蛛网头
Nice of you to make it, web head.
术士, 桑德拉, 噪音和陷阱
Wizard, thundra, klaw and trapster.
又称邪恶四人组
Otherwise known as the frightful four.
我们得到消息说他们要闯入一间仓库
We got a tip they were gonna break into a warehouse
仓库是奥斯集团所有, 奥斯集团!
Owned by oscorp. oscorp!
我知道, 这个世界真小, 是吧?
I know, small world, huh?
我们的队伍非常团结,看见我们战斗的风貌了吗?
The team is really gelled. see how we're fighting?
真是漂亮的干活, 而我就是他们的领袖
It's a thing of beauty, and i'm their leader.
你等会儿行吗? 我这儿正说话呢
Do you mind? i'm trying to talk here.
如果我能让彼得·帕克那边的生活
If I could just get the peter parker side of things
跟这一样顺畅, 我就发达了
Working as smoothly, i'd be golden.
可别告诉我, 陷阱
Don't tell me, trapster.
这是个...
This is--
陷阱
A trap.
再见了, 英雄们!
Goodbye, heroes!
我们就把你们跟耻辱, 和上千个机器杀手留这儿了
We leave you with your shame, and a thousand killer robots.
我就为这个翘掉了500美元一个的汉堡?
I skipped out on a $500 hamburger for this?!
好吧, 伙计们! 我们为此训练过
All right, people! we've trained for this.
咱们干掉它们
Let's take 'em out!
真不敢相信我们那么容易就上当了!
I can't believe we were sucked in so easily!
平心静气, 朋友
Try to maintain calm, friend.
我很平静
I am calm.
这就是我, 我平静就这样!
This is me, being calm!
我不知道你们有什么好叽歪的
I don't know what you all are bugging over.
但它们挺好对付的
These guys are light weights.
新星说得对, 这一点都不难
Nova's right. that wasn't so tough.
小蜘蛛说得好像这些机器人是大麻烦
Spidey made these octobots sound like they'd be real trouble.
伙计们, 蜘蛛侠在哪儿?
Guys, where's spider-man?
梅婶婶? 哈利? MJ?
Aunt may? Harry? m.j.?
没事, 皮特, 有那么一分钟还以为
There there, peter. thought for a minute
你要离我们而去了
You were going to leave us.
我确实离开了啊, 那不是个梦
But I did leave. and it wasn't a dream.
而是个地方
It was a place.
有你, 还有你
And you were there. and you were there.
而且你, 你是个... 等等
And you, you were... wait a second.
为什么所有人都是黑白的
Why is everybody in black and white?
我... 我在哪儿?
Where...where am I?
绝对出了堪萨斯州了
Definitely not in kansas anymore.
怎么啦? "绿野仙踪"可是经典
What? it's a classic.
你和你的大嘴巴
You and your incessant blather,
你从来不会闭嘴吗?!
Do you ever shut up?!
章鱼博士?
Doctor octopus?
呃! 你看起来真恶心
Ugh! you look horrible.
你的机械手臂呢?
Where are your robot arms?
我都不确定是不是还能叫你章鱼博士了
I'm not even sure I can call you doc ock anymore.
大概水母博士或是鼻涕虫博士吧, 但也只能到此为止
Doc jellyfish or doc slug maybe, but that's as far as I go.
哈, 要联络你那帮朋友可有点困难
Heh, you might find it difficult to call your friends,
我把你的小通讯器拿走了
Seeing as I took your little communicator.
我可不像你, 我从我的错误中学习
Unlike you, I learn from my mistakes.
没有铁人, 没有神盾, 没有朋友来救你了
No iron man, no shield, no friends are coming to save you.
今晚就剩我们三个了
Tonight it will be just the three of us.
你, 我...
You, me...
和我的复仇
And my revenge.
你能把复仇配着薯条端给我吗?
Could you serve up that revenge with a side of fries?
我今晚没吃饭
I missed out on dinner tonight and
等等, 有了--
Wait a second. I got it--
- 河豚博士! - 啊!
- doctor blowfish! - grrr!
奥克塔维厄斯已经夺走了小蜘蛛的通讯器
Octavius has scrambled spidey's communicator.
它现在从好几个地点发送假信号
It's giving off ghost signals at multiple locations.
我派了人全城地毯式搜寻蜘蛛侠
I've got teams scouring the city for spider-man,
但情况不太妙, 章鱼计划很周密
But it doesn't look good. ock has planned this well.
我有新消息会通知你们
I'll update you if I get anything.
他是我们的队友,我们得做点什么
He's our teammate. we gotta do something.
- 我们不能坐在这儿等 - 没人说我们该...
- we can't just sit and wait. - nobody's saying we should--
等等
Wait.
- 不, 不是吧! - 别踩扁它
- oh, no you don't! - don't smash it.
这个章鱼机器人要去个地方
That octobot is heading someplace.
我们也是
And so are we.
哈, 我跟你说我很怕痒痒
Hah. i'll have you know i'm ticklish.
啊!
Ouch!
嘿!
Hey!
你到底盯上我多久了, 臭章鱼博士?
Exactly how long have you been after me, doctor "octopest"?
为什么?
And why?
我一直想复制你的力量
I have been attempting to replicate your powers
有段时间了. 有几次我都快要成功了
For some time.on several occasions I have come close.
比如说-- 毒液?
That looks a lot like-- venom?!
是的, 你可以把他看做近亲
Yes. you could consider him a close relative.
他干的
He did it.
我可没看出相似之处
I don't see the resemblance.
毒液还存在缺陷
Venom had limitations.
- 他很难控制 - 你还说呢?
- he was uncontrollable. - ya think?
有了你DNA的新样本
With this new sample of your DNA,
我就能合成出更有趣的新版本...
I'll be able to synthesize a far more interesting strain...
它会有无限潜力
One that holds infinite new possibilities.
它会由我控制
One that I control.
现在我需要的就是实验对象
Now all I need is my test subject.
吃了一惊吧?
Astonished?
超级英雄第一讲, 博士
Super hero 101, doc.
你絮絮叨叨的时候, 我溜出来了
While you were yammering, I slipped out.
没打中!
Missed me!
又没打中!
但我可没中意你!
But I didn't miss you!
博士, 你得找点更好的帮手. 你付他们工资吗?
Doc, you gotta get better help. are you paying them
还是他们只能拿到学分?
Or do they only get class credit?
这个大概会很贵吧
That was probably really expensive.
阿哦!
Oops!
不. 不
No. no.
就差一点
So close.
我不想大放厥词... 哈哈, 我说了大放
I don't wanna toot my own horn-- heh, heh, I said toot.
但是我整惨了你... 又一次
But I just punked you-- again.
蜘蛛感应?
Spidey-sense?
好吧博士, 你的触手上还有什么把戏?
Okay doc, what else you got up your tentacle?
诺曼...
Norman...
奥斯本?
Osborn?
等等, 你是在用这种
Wait, are you telling me,
"我刚电击你了哥们"的方式告诉我
In that "I just tased you bro" sort of way that
你为章鱼博士工作?
You work for doc ock?
为他工作? 哦, 才不是呢
Work for him? oh, hardly.
奥托是我的员工
Otto is my employee.
我雇他来取得你的DNA
I hired him to obtain your DNA.
原来你是我的粉丝啊, 诺曼
Didn't know you were such a fan, norman.
要不我给你个亲笔签名算了?
Couldn't I have just given you a signed autograph instead?
安静!
Be silent!
这样的能力浪费在这样的白痴身上
Such power wasted on such a fool.
我会把它用在比阻止犯罪
I will put it to better use than stopping petty crimes
和开幼稚玩笑更伟大的事业上
And cracking childish jokes.
想想看, 一队永不停歇的蜘蛛军队
Imagine, an unstoppable arachnid army
在我的掌控下
Under my control.
我会轻易赢得竞争
I will crush the competition.
神盾和斯塔克都将无法撼动
Neither shield nor stark will be able to challenge
奥斯本的无上地位
Oscorp supremacy.
这才是对能量的真正利用
That is the true use of power.
我最好哥们的老爸是个杀人狂
My best friend's dad is a homicidal maniac
还一直想毁灭我? 我怎么会没发现?
Who's been trying to destroy me? how did I miss that?
好吧, 这么看的话...
Well, when you put it that way...
我关注你很久了
I've been following you for so long,
我知道你的一切
I know everything about you.
我都觉得我们是一家人了
I almost feel like we're family.
你可不知道啊
You have no idea.
你做了什么?
What did you do?!
我给了你你要的一切, 诺曼
I just gave you everything you ever wanted, norman.
这个就当是我的辞职信吧
Consider this my resignation.
如今背弃别人可不赚钱啊
Doesn't pay to turn your back on anybody today.
啊! 你还能再走慢点吗?!
Argh! could you possibly go any slower?!
耐心点
Patience.
他最终会把我们带到蜘蛛侠那儿的
Eventually it'll lead us to spider-man.
我们可没时间等到" 最终"!
We don't have time for "eventually"!
小蜘蛛正有麻烦呢, 我们得赶快做点什么NSpidey's in trouble now. we need to do something fast.
我们需要速度
Speed is what we need.
新星, 你能给这个机器人提供能量吗?
Nova, can you energize that robot?
好主意, 很高兴我想过这办法
A good idea. glad I thought of it.
快点, 水桶头!
Move it, buckethead!
奥托! 为什么?
Otto! why?
我为你做了那么多!
After all i've done for you!
为我? 为我?!
For me? for me?!
你把我当做奴隶使唤!
You treated me like a slave!
把我的实验室连带我一起毁了!
Destroyed my lab with me in it!
是你把我变成这样的!
You turned me into this!
你为我做的只是给我痛苦
All you've done for me is give me pain!
他说的有道理, 诺曼
He's got a point there, norman.
真是史上最坏的老板
Worst boss ever.
反抗是没用的, 诺曼
It's no use fighting it, Osborn.
你... 你背叛了我!
You-- you've betrayed me!
你这个自大的小丑!
You arrogant buffoon!
如果我破解了公式, 你不觉得
If I had cracked the formula, don't you think I would've
我会先用在自己身上吗? 我刚给你注射了
Used it on myself? i've just injected you
毒液与蜘蛛侠DNA的融合物
With a fusion of venom's and spider-man's DNA.
如果我的计算正确
If my calculations are correct,
它应该会得出很有趣的结果
It should produce a most interesting result.
只是这一次, 它由我控制
Only this time, one that I control.
看起来大人们有好多事要谈啊
Looks like the grown-ups have some talking to do.
那我就...
I'm just gonna--
哦! 好疼啊!
Ouch! that hurt!
你想知道最棒的部分, 奥斯本
You wanna know the most delicious part, Osborn,
你这个自大的蠢货? - 哇!
- you pompous halfwit? - whoa!
你谋划了那么久怎么抓住
After all your schemes of catching
蜘蛛侠并偷取他的DNA
spider-man and stealing his DNA
你从未意识到...
You never realized...
他一直都属于你
He belonged to you all along.
他的力量院子奥斯集团的科技
His powers are a product of oscorp technology!
虽然我还没弄清是怎么发生的
Although I have yet to discover how it happened,
但蜘蛛侠是你最大的成就!
Spider-man is your greatest accomplishment!
奥斯集团实验室校外考察!
School field trip to oscorp laboratories!
小蜘蛛起源第3043条
Spidey origin take three thousand and forty three.
看...高中生...
See-- high school student--
课外考察... 突然, 好痛!
Class field trip-- suddenly, ouch!
蜘蛛咬了... 基因改造的蜘蛛...
Spider bite... genetically enhanced spider...
血液沸腾, DNA改变
blood burns, DNA alters
身体变化... 啪嗒砰, 吧嗒蹦!
Body transforms-- bada bing, bada boom!
神奇蜘蛛侠就诞生了
The amazing spider-man is born!
但什么样的疯狂科学能创造出如此奇迹?
But what mad science made such miracles possible?
等一下, 等一下...
Wait for it, wait for it--
嘣! 大亮!
Pow! screen gold!
神奇蜘蛛侠由诺曼奥斯本创造
That amazing spider was invented by norman Osborn.
呃! 怎么突然感觉这么难受?
Ugh! why do I suddenly feel so skeevy?
就艺术层面来说, 复仇真是美丽
As an art form, revenge is nothing if not beautiful.
现在还得找出
Now there's still the matter of
造就你的技术
finding out what makes you tech
- 啊! - 幸好
- ugh! - fortunately,
我不再需要你活着了
I no longer need you alive for that.
事实上, 解剖才是我的最爱
In fact, dissection is desirable.
额, 听来很有趣, 让我查查日程表
Aw, sounds like fun. let me check my schedule.
不如把时间改到... 永不? 你说行不?
How 'bout...never? that work for ya?
弗里的走狗? 怎么这么快?!
Fury's lapdogs? so soon?!
- 小蜘蛛, 你没伤着吧? - 抓住奥斯本
- spidey, are you hurt? - get Osborn!
你不明白!
You don't get it!
现在的问题已经不是章鱼博士了!
This isn't about doc ock anymore!
他在分散你的注意力!
He's distracting you!
嘿, 诺曼, 你看起来有点绿
Hey, norman. you're looking a little green.
也有点魔
And Gobliny.
说真的, 我该怎么跟哈利说?
Seriously, what am I gonna tell Harry?
哦, 哦哦哦! 快赢了
Oh, ho, ho, ho! ownage.
你这下可被我虐爽了
You just got beat with a fail bat!
是吗? 你老爸可是个怪物呢!
Oh, yeah? you dad's a monster!
我留了1000美元给你们买吃的
I left a $1,000 in case you get hungry.
一会儿见, 儿子
See you later, son.
我赐给了你新生, 诺曼
I've given you new life, norman.
我已经去除了你身上每一处瑕疵与不足
I've removed every imperfection and weakness.
我让你回归真正的自我
I've turned you into the true you.
一只怪物. 一只异形
A monster. a grotesque.
一只绿魔
A Goblin.
我的绿魔
My Goblin.
好了, 奥斯本
Now now, Osborn.
你就这样对待你的博士?
Is this any way to treat your doctor?
我给你力量可不会
I wouldn't have given you power
没点适当的控制措施
Without a proper way of controlling it.
看来我把你弄得比我期望的要好
It appears I made you better than even I suspected.
我可能还得做一点调整
I may have to make a few adjustments!
别忘了, 是我创造了你
Don't forget. I made you.
你属于我!
You belong to me!
我们为什么要跑啊?
Why are we running?
我们应该留下结束这场战斗
We should've stayed and finished the fight.
我们没在逃跑, 我们在引他出来
We're not running. we're drawing him out.
我们需要尼克·弗里或者钢铁侠
We need nick Fury or iron man
或者其他有合适武器的人
Or someone with the right tools.
为什么? 我们能搞定那玩意儿
Why? we can handle that thing.
那玩意儿不是什么路人, 那是诺曼奥斯本
That thing's not just some guy. it's norman Osborn.
他是我最好朋友的爸爸
He's my best friend's dad.
好吧, 从这声音听来
Yeah well, from the sounds of it,
你好基友的老爹想和你好好玩玩
Your bff's dad wants to play.
神力侠!
Power man!
铁拳! 坚持住, 伙计
Iron fist! stay with me, buddy.
奥斯本!
Osborn!
你个恶心的怪物!
You sick freak!
这是为了我的队伍!
This is for what you've done to my team!
这是为了你儿子!
And to your own son!
我该把你打成泥...
I should beat you into a paste...
但是我不会这么做
But i'm not going to.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
你不必当这个...
You don't have to be this...
这个绿魔
This green Goblin.
让我帮助你
Let me help you.
诺曼, 我知道你的意识还在!
Norman, I know you're in there!
你心里还有人性! 想想你儿子, 哈利!
You're still human inside! think of your son, Harry!
无论章鱼博士对你做了什么,
Whatever doc ock did to you,
也改变不了你爱你儿子的事实
It didn't change the fact that you love your son.
诺曼, 拜托了!
Norman, please!
奥斯本...
Osborn...
- 不再存在! - 呃!
- no more! - ugh!
只存在... 绿魔!
Only...Goblin!
很抱歉, 奥斯本先生
I'm sorry, mr. Osborn.
但是我的队伍, 就像我的家人
But my team, they're like my family.
如果必须打倒你才能救他们...
And if I gotta take you out to save them...
我就会这么做!
Then that's what i'm gonna do!
小蜘蛛. 绿魔
Spider. Goblin.
都流着同样的血
Same blood.
小蜘蛛, 绿魔
Spider. Goblin.
都是一家人
Family.
我可真没看出相似之处
I don't see the resemblance.
神盾特工扇形排开
Shield agents fan out.
叫医务人员过来
And get some medics down here.
蜘蛛侠
Spider-man.
你可来得真是时候
Just in the nick of time...
嘿 尼克...
Heh...nick.
老爸?
Dad?
老爸!
Dad!
- 不能超过这条线! - 爸爸!
- No one beyond this point! - Dad!
儿子!
Son!
你们小队做的很好
You did good, team.
神盾正在追捕绿魔
Shield is tracking the Goblin.
我应该想到的
I should've seen it coming.
我让我跟哈利的友谊干扰了判断
I let my friendship with Harry cloud my judgment.
最糟的是, 绿魔还未绳之以法
Worst of all, green Goblin is still out there.
说实话吧, 弗里
Let's face it, Fury.
你想让我成为终极蜘蛛侠
You tried to make me the ultimate spider-man.
可我却只是终极大废物
All I am is the ultimate failure.
- 我们会抓到奥斯本的. - 我们?!
- We'll get Osborn. - We?!
你不明白, 弗里, 这可不是"我们"的事
You don't get it, Fury. there is no "we".
那是我的DNA, 我朋友的父亲, 我的问题!
It's my DNA, my friend's dad, my problem!
我原本独来独往, 但后来我脑子糊涂
I was a solo act. but against my better judgment,
加入了这个团队, 现在我已经把所有我在乎的人
I joined this crew, and now i've put everyone I care about
置于危险的境地
In harm's way.
我不该让别人因我受到伤害
No one else gets hurt because of me.
这是我弄出的乱子, 该由我收拾
It's my mess. I have to clean it up.
我会解决这个绿魔, 并且...
I'm gonna take care of the green Goblin and...
我会单独行动
I'm gonna do it alone.
@Slomo-Lu小鱼[新浪微博]
欢迎关注微博了解最新动画讯息
翻译 小玮
特效 Lu小鱼
校对 gegemoon
压制 魔芋
时间轴 小河